Process for adding new characters to the database

If adding characters in bulk, it is recommended to complete them in an assembly line manner;
for each step performed on a specific character, do so for each of the characters you wish to
add before moving on to the next step.

For any questions, contact Thomas Parker at parker.tom.f@gmail.com.

Note that steps 1 and 4 must be done on a Mac operating system.


Step 1: Creating Images
 1. Open XCode.
 2. Open ChineseCharacterProject.
 3. Open dictionary.json
 4. Copy the definition for the last character listed ({"character":"四" ... "]},)
    Consider, for example, the last character to be 四.
 5. Paste the copied code below the definition for last character.
 6. Replace the text of the last character (i.e. "四") in the copied code blocks with a 
    new character (e.g. "五", "六", "七"...).
 8. Set the destination device (Product -> Destination) to the largest iPad available.
 9. Run the simulator (cmd-R).
10. Navigate in the simulation to character selection, and select each of the characters you
    wish to add, then press the Practice Selected button.
11. Open the screenshot tool (cmd-shift-4).
12. Take a screenshot of the entire drawing canvas, containing the first character you selected,
    then proceed to the next character and repeat.
13. Open the first screenshot image in the Preview application.
14. Click the button with a circle surrounding the tip of a pen. It should open a toolbar.
    (the button next to the search bar)
15. Click the resize button (a box with two diagonal arrows pointing out).
16. Change the width to 500 pixels. The height should change accordingly.


Step 2: Creating Bezier Code From the Image
 1. Navigate to http://www.victoriakirst.com/beziertool/
    Note that this tool has some bugs. It may simplify the process if between creating the Bezier
    code for each character, you refresh the page.
    If you have not used this tool before, it is recommended to play with it so as to understand
    the functionality and how to manipulate Bezier curves before moving on.
    If you want to better understand Bezier curves, either to aid with this process or more
    mathematically, information at both of those levels of detail can be found at:
    https://javascript.info/bezier-curve
 2. Navigate to http://imgur.com in another tab.
 3. Click the New post button on the top left, and upload your image.
 4. On the Bezier tool, paste the image URL into the image URL text box.
 5. Click the Set Canvas Background button. You will have to do so twice. 
    As stated, the tool has bugs.
 6. On the Bezier tool, adding and moving points, create the Bezier path of the first stroke of 
    the character. Ensure that the ordering of the points is the same as the direction the stroke 
    is supposed to be.
    Ensure not to let the curves twist in a hook shape at the end. For points at the beginning or
    the end, do so by making sure their corresponding floating control point is on the inside 
    (i.e on the side of the line).
    For other points this is less likely to be the case, but to verify, move the floating control
    point around one on the line.
 7. Copy the code generated to the right to your clipboard, and paste it into a text file.
    For each straight line in the Bezier curve, replace the corresponding text in the generated 
    code that reads "bezierCurveTo" with "lineTo".
 8. Repeat steps 3 and 4 for the remaining strokes of the character, pasting the new code below
    that of previous strokes in the same text file.
 9. Above this code, add a #, after which you can label the character. 
    For example, you could write "#6" to label 六. This does not have to correspond to the 
    character, and can even just be "#" by itself. This label will be in the SVG file later.
10. For each other character you intend to generate SVG code for, paste the generated code for its
    strokes in the same text file, separeted by the aforementioned #s.


Step 3: Creating SVGs from the Bezier Code
    Note that your device may not have Python installed, in which case you must do so, at
    https://www.python.org/downloads/
 1. Open the command line interface on your computer.
    (Command Prompt for Windows, Terminal for Mac).
 2. Navigate on the command line to where you saved the text file generated in step 2.
    To do so, observe that the command line shows a current directory. 
    For example, "C:\Users\YourName"
    To go to a folder in the YourName folder, type "cd exampleFolder", and then press enter.
    The current directory should now show "C:\Users\YourName\exampleFolder"
    To go back a folder, type "cd .."
    Use these techniques to complete this step.
 3. Copy make_svg.py from ChineseCharacterProject to where you saved the Bezier code text files.
 4. On a Windows computer, type "dir" into the command line and press enter. On a Mac computer,
    type "ls" and press enter. It will list all the files in the current directory. This should
    include the text file with the code generated in step 2, as well as make_svg.py.
 3. On the command line, type "python make_svg.py exampleBezierTextFileName.txt".
    This will generate a text file in the same directory named "strokes.txt".
    If you open the text file, you will see the SVG data for each character, separated
    by the label given after the "#" in the original Bezier text file, from step 2.9.
    If you already had a file named "strokes.txt", the new additions will follow what was
    already there.


Step 4: Adding the SVGs and Other Character Information to dictionary.json
 1. Return to dictionary.json as in step 1.
 2. For each of the characters you added in step 1.5 as copies of the last character, replace
    the text in brackets after '"strokes":', the strokes field, with the new corresponding text
    from strokes.txt.
    For example, using the same example from step 1, replace the copied SVG of 四 with those
    of 五, 六, 七, etc.
 3. Change the definition and pinyin fields to the definition and pinyin of 五, 六, 七.
 4. The other fields (decomposition, radical, matches, points) are unnecessary in the current
    build of the application, and will most likely be removed in the future. So you can
    leave those fields as those of 四. 
    However, if you like, or the current developers do use these fields, you may find appropriate
    values for over 9000 characters here:
    https://github.com/skishore/makemeahanzi/blob/master/dictionary.txt


You are now done! Test your new characters by simulating the application again as in step 1.